Everyday,
Camille uses applications
on her phone
and they are very useful
For example
to know the weather,
to check her bank account,
or her glycemia
because Camille is diabetic.
But, what Camille doesn't know
is that in each of these applications
there are trackers.
These trackers have been added
when the application was created
with the sole purpose of
collecting data.
Such as
where Camille lives
where she works
or the drugstore
where she gets her treatment.
These trackers allow the person
who created the application to
first, be able to know who uses the application
to know the audience,
but also,
if they offer advertising
to target it as much as they can.
In fact, the more targeted an ad is,
the more efficient it becomes,
so the more money it makes.
Finally,
the creator of the app
can sell the data collected by the trackers.
But Camille does not like that very much,
all these trackers
collecting things about her without her knowning.
So now, Camille,
when she installs a new application
she goes first to the Exodus Privacy website.
This platform analyzes
the free applications available on Google Store
and detects the presence or the lack of trackers on it.