Previously, in Camille's adventures
Camile use every day
some applications on her smartphone
but she discovered the existance of trackers
those little piece of code
who collect informations about her.
She realizes
that this data can affect
very sensitive domains
like her illness or her sexual orientation.
Camille ask her self
How those trackers came into the applicationss?
An Exodus Privacy video
In order to answer this question
Camille must understand
how applications are made
An application, it's a little bit like a car.
They all have a goal:
helping Cammille to do her shopping,
going gambling,
or post a package.
They are both complex to build.
a lot of stuff
and many differents professions participate to the creation.
In order to build the engine,
there is two choices for the engineers.
create the engine from scratch
or use an already created engine.
It's the same for an application!
Developers,
the person who write code in computer language
could choose to use an already done piece of code
in library code
or write all the application code, from scratch.
Ok. So when did the trackers come into the applications?
A traker, it's a piece of code.
So someone has to write at a time
in the application program
It could be from the persons who wrote the applications
for example to have revenues for adverts.
But some time those persons does not even know they've added a tracker.
For example, if a developer use a piece of code wrote by others
which use geoloc whitout her knowledge,
the final application will have a tracker.
And if Camille install it on her smartphone,
she will be tracked through this
As we can find the same engine in differents cars,
We can find same trackers in many applications.
To keep an eye on Camille adventure,
you can watch the two first episode
and subscribe to the Exodus Privacy YouTube Channel
or find them on Peertube
Follow us on mastodon, twitter or Facebook.